The entire hill looks like osmanthus flower cake!
怎麼整個山丘看起來都像桂花糕？
Stop nonsense!
少廢話
Will you ever starve back in the capital?
回到了江都，你還怕沒有吃的嗎？
Take it.
接著
Brother Gao, a bandit's hideout is found three miles ahead!
高大哥，前面三里外發現一個山寨
It's true! What a surprise!
想不到是真的
Legend has it that the Desert Camels have killed
傳說沙漠血駝那幫毛賊殺人殺得太多
so many that even their blades have turned black.
就連這刀刃都被血染成黑色的
Predict it.
你算一算
The west the will of God, the north the barbaric...
西天璣，北蚩尤…
Commander... let's hurry.
都尉…我們還是趕路吧
It is fortune or misfortune?
到底是凶是吉啊？
It's neither fortune or misfortune.
此卦非凶，亦非吉
Hey... come on!
哎呀…來呀！
Go!
來呀！
Beauty...
美女
are you hungry?
你餓了吧？
What would you like to eat?
你想吃什麼？
Congratulations, boss...
恭喜大王，恭喜大王…
Say it and I'll get you whatever you want!
你說你要什麼，我全都給你
Really?
真的嗎？
Really. My heart is now yours.
真的，我的心都已經是你的了
Hey, caught it.
哎呀，抓到了
It's on fire...
起火啦…
Sneak attack! Chase them...
有人偷襲！快追…
Shoot!
放箭！
Come on! I'll take you away!
來，我帶你走
Come on!
來呀！
Hold me tight!
抱穩！
Sacrifice our lives!
拋頭顱兮！
For the sake of our parents!
為爹為娘！
Spill our blood!
撒熱血兮！
For the sake of our home!
為保家鄉！
Walk a million miles!
經萬里兮！
And kill the bandits of the desert!
殺沙匪兮！
To save the beauty!
為救嬌娘！
Put on our golden armors!
穿金甲兮！
They're back! They're back! General is back!
回來了！回來了！將軍回來了！
You're grown up!
都長那麼大了
We saved her halfway.
她是我們在路上救回來的女子
Her parents are dead.
父母雙亡
Why disappeared?
為什麼不見了？
Someone's knocking the door?
將軍，外面有人敲門？
Open the door.
開門
Mistress!
夫人！
Can't we just send him to an inn?
怎麼不把他送到客棧去？
Bullshit!
胡扯什麼！
We're brothers.
我們怎麼也是兄弟一場
And it's New Year.
再說也過年了
Who?
誰呀？
He's back.
他回來了
You're all here.
你們都來啦
Miss Xiaowei.
小唯姐
It's so cold outside.
外面天氣冷
- Drink some hot water. - Give it to me!
喝點熱水      來，請給我
Have some osmanthus flower cakes!
吃點桂花糕吧
Okay, thank you.
好，謝謝你
Thanks, Miss Xiaowei.
謝謝小唯姐
Brother Gao Xiang, drink while it's hot.
高翔大哥，趁熱喝
So attentive.
你真周到
Who is this man?
他是誰呀？
He...
他…
Right there!
在那裡！
General...
將軍…
General, are you okay?
將軍，你怎麼啦？
Why didn't you wait for us?
你怎麼不等我們？
General...
將軍…
Have you gone mad?
你是不是瘋了？
Hundreds of gangsters here!
這裡有上百的匪賊
You said
你曾經說過
we're all brothers who'd die together.
我們這隊人都是同生共死的兄弟
We must go home all alive!
一定要活著歸鄉的
I'll never lead you.
我不會再帶你們
Brother Yong
勇哥
- General... - Brother Yong.
將軍…      勇哥…
General, are you okay...
將軍，你怎麼了？
General...
將軍…
Freeze!
站住！
You won't!
你哪裡都不准去
A soldier like you can't go as you wish!
軍隊豈容你說走便走？
This is desertion...
身為統領，丟甲棄職
and the penalty is death!
我可以用軍法處置你！
No!
不要！
No...
不要…
Get away!
讓開！
Leave me!
放開我！
Everybody, take care.
大家保重
- General... - Brother Yong.
將軍…      勇哥…
Have you contacted him?
你聯絡過他嗎？
No.
沒有
Don't you want him to come back?
你不想他回來嗎？
Of course I do!
怎麼會
Perhaps he can catch the guy...
他這個時候回來
who tore the man's heart out.
還能幫我抓拿那個挖心的傢伙
I just never thought
只是我沒想到
he'd been dejected like this.
他潦倒成現在這個樣子
We're married already. How about letting him stay?
我們已經是夫妻，請他留下來吧
Do you know?
你知道嗎？
I've been worried about you every day.
我每天都在擔心你
Be careful.
小心一些
I won't eat it. Go give others to share.
我不吃，你拿去分了吧
Thank you, Miss Xiaowei.
謝謝小唯姐
Really won't eat?
你真的不吃了？
No, I won't.
不吃
Then I'm going.
那我出去
I've sliced them for you from six humans.
六個人的，都替你切片了
Why killed so many? How to eat them all at once?
殺這麼多人幹嘛？我吃得下嗎？
For you to choose. It's just a few.
讓你挑嘛，就幾個人而已
I don't mean to feel bad for them.
我不是可惜那些人
But you've made a lot of work for Wang Sheng.
而是你害得王生天天往外跑
I hardly see him these days.
害我連見他的機會都少了
You can simply kill his wife!
那你殺他夫人不就可以了？
You're so disgusting.
你真的很噁心
Who is it from?
這是誰的？
Young master of Golden Restaurant.
萬利飯莊的太子爺
That fatso.
哦，那個胖子
And this?
這個呢？
Foreman of the dyehouse.
染布坊的工頭
He's ugly!
他很醜呀
It's said that the uglier the human heart...
不是說我們要成魔
the better to be ultimate in black magic.
吃的人心越醜惡就越有用嗎？
If you want a pretty heart, try Wang Sheng's one.
你要英俊的，吃那個王生哥的心吧
You're wasting your time.
你是在浪費時間
We've been here for nearly three months.
我們呆在這都快三個月啦
He will love me.
他會愛我的
I don't believe I'll lose to that stupid woman!
我就不信我會輸給那個蠢女人
Why don't you just be his concubine?
你要當個妾又有何難？
Concubine? Why do I need to be?
妾？我為什麼要當妾？
What I want to be is his wife.
我要做的是王夫人
Listen. I shall be Mrs. Wang.
我告訴你，我一定會是王夫人
So you want to give up your training?
那你要成魔的修煉就放下啦？
I have plenty of time.
我有的是時間嘛
But your skin won't wait.
可是你的皮囊沒有時間
You need more hearts...
你再不多吃一點人心
to keep your human skin from rotting.
你的人皮就要壞掉啦
Sure! Therefore, I've got to find a way out
對呀！所以我要想一個辦法
so I can stop myself eating such gross!
讓自己不再用吃那麼噁心的東西
Not woken up yet?
還沒有醒嗎？
No.
沒有
Let me get you some tea.
我給你倒杯茶吧
Peirong. I haven't slept a wink for days.
佩蓉，我幾天幾夜沒睡
Peirong... I've drunk too much!
佩蓉…我喝得太多了
Brother Yong.
勇哥
You've woken up.
你醒啦
Sorry.
不好意思
Thanks.
打擾了
I'm going!
我走了
Brother Yong.
勇哥
Hey brother,
這位大哥
It's New Year's Eve. At least stay...
年三十啦，要不要留下來
with us for the...
跟我們一起吃一頓年…
No, thanks!
用不了客氣
Brother Yong, just wait a moment.
勇哥，你等一等
I've got something to return to you.
我有樣東西要還給你
Brother Yong, your sword.
勇哥，你的刀
Wish you good luck.
大吉大利
I just wondered where you've gone.
唉！還以為你跑去哪裡了
So righteous that you haven't left me alone.
有義氣啊，沒把我扔掉
Brother Yong...
勇哥…
We've just come to the commander's house to fine you!
勇哥，我們剛去都尉府看你
Stop it. Get me some food.
不要說了，給我弄點吃的
Okay, okay...
好，好…
Give me...
給我來…
Brother Yong, where've you been for the last two years?
勇哥，這兩年你都去了哪？
Sure! Where?
對呀！去哪？
Brother Yong.
勇哥
Have you suddenly come back for anything?
這次回來，是不是聽說什麼事情啦？
What's happened here?
這裡出了什麼事？
Nothing...
沒有…
Waiter, any spare room?
小二，有沒有房間？
Yes, sure...
有，有…
Please pay a deposit at the counter first, sir.
爺，請您到我們掌櫃那先交個訂錢吧
I'm leaving my horse here,
我連馬都留下了
and you think I'll run away?
難道沒有訂錢給你嗎？
Okay, fine...
好，好…
Waiter, don't forget to look after my horse!
小二，別忘了把我的馬餵好
I will, I guarantee. Rest assured!
保證把你的馬餵好，放心吧
Please pay a deposit first, sir.
客官，請您先交個訂錢吧
I'm leaving my horse here...
我連馬都留下
and you think I'll run away?
你還有什麼不放心的？
Take care of my horse!
好好照顧我的馬！
I will!
得了您的！
Take care, sir. Happy new year!
客官，請慢走，新年吉祥！
Let's go.
走了
Waiter, it's a big inn; nothing more than that.
店小二，你這麼大的客棧什麼都沒有
Not even a slice of meat?
連一片肉都沒有
They've all gone home for new year,
都回家過年去了
so has the chef.
連我們大廚也剛回家了
Let it be... any wine?
算了，算了…酒有吧？
Sure... l'll take it now!
有…我幫你拿去
A bottle of best spring liquor!
我要一瓶九醞春
Sir, it's just sold out!
爺呀，這酒剛賣完
She's taken all the rest.
剩下的，都給她拿走了
Sir, please choose others.
爺，換別的吧？
Come here. Be my guest!
過來，我請客
Please!
請吧
Thank you.
謝了
Waiter.
小二
Waiter, one more bottle!
再拿一個碗來，小二
Waiter...
小二…
No need. Here.
不用啦，哪
I'll give this pair ofjade pendants to who you love!
你喜歡誰，就把這一對玉珮送給誰
Don't be like that.
不要這樣
We always come back alive...
我們每次上戰場
after each battle, don't we?
不是都好好的回來嗎？
Say it after I'm back.
回來再說
Brother Yong.
勇哥
Come on. Don't always cry!
不要哭，你每次都這麼愛哭
Smile. You look much prettier when you smile!
笑笑看，要笑才漂亮嘛
Come on... smile! I will be back!
來，嘻…笑笑，等我回來
Let's go!
我們走
We'll be back.
我們會回來的
How're you doing?
吃過了嗎？
Where have you been the last two years?
你這兩年都去哪了？
You're here just to ask...
你來不是為了問我
such dull questions?
這些無聊的問題吧？
I suspect if there's a demon in our house.
我懷疑家裡來了一個妖怪
Three months ago,
三個月以前
When Brother Sheng was back after encountering bandits in the desert,
生哥從陰山回來，遇到一群沙匪
he rescued a young woman with nowhere to stay.
他救了一個無家可歸的女孩子
Elder sister.
姐姐
Her names is Xiaowei.
她叫小唯
She claimed to be daughter of Gao Kun, a wealthy silk businessman.
她說她是蘇州絲綢商人高昆的女兒
Her parents were framed and killed by corrupt officials
因為遭狗官陷害，家破人亡
and she was sold to the bandits...
被賣到沙匪的手中…
Tell me.
你說
So many people love Xiaowei. Who will she go for?
這麼多人喜歡小唯，她會喜歡誰？
How do I guess what's in a woman's heart?
你們女兒家的心事我怎麼知道？
Suddently,
突然
there appeared an assassin in the city...
城裡來了一個挖心的劍客
who tore out the hearts of so many.
死了很多人
Even the city's magistrate ran away last night.
管城的縣官昨天晚上跑了
All the guards have hidden away.
縣裡的官差都躲起來了
No one dare patrol at night.
誰都不敢夜巡
The new magistrate has not yet come.
現在新的官員還沒有到任
But there can't be without law in the city.
可城裡不可以一日沒有王法
Brothers, we will now take charge of the city
兄弟們都給我披甲上陣，由我們來管
till the new magistrate takes up his post.
直到新的縣官到任為止
Are you ready?
大家準備好了嗎？
- The assassin keeps killing. - Ready!
劍客繼續殺人      準備好！
- Nobody can deal with it. - Go!
誰也拿他沒辦法      去吧！
The only thing he can do is step up the patrols every night.
他唯一能做的，就是每夜加強巡查
Then some times later, people start to
不知道從什麼時候開始
doubt if they're all the work of evil demons.
不少人懷疑，是妖的所作所為
Miss, try this hairpin. It's beautiful.
小姐，試一下這款釵子吧，很漂亮的
These are the pearl powder.
這些啊，是我們店裡剛剛到的
New arrival.
一些珍珠粉
Do you want to try it?
你要不要試試看？
Miss, what you want is this, right?
小姐，你要的就是這個吧
Why should I buy this?
我為什麼要買這個？
You have to!
你要買這個
I'll take them all.
我全都要啦
You gotta put on makeup!
你要去換妝
Sure! I gotta put on makeup!
對，我要去換妝
This way, please.
裡邊請
Is she really an evil demon?
她真的是妖嗎？
I can't help you.
我幫不了你啦
Let me find you a man of power!
我幫你找個高人吧
Stay back. Back off...
讓開，退後…
The Taoist priest is dead, with his heart digged out...
賽神仙死了，賽神仙被挖了心…
The killer is a big, tall guy.
挖心的，是個身材高大的男人
I have told
這件事情
no one but only you and another guy.
除了你，我只告訴了一個人
He is the Taoist priest.
就是賽神仙
He called me to take Xiaowei to the Taoist temple
他叫我把小唯帶到逍遙觀
but he was dead the very next day!
怎知道第二天他就死啦
How horrible!
多恐怖呀！
Okay!
好啦…
I promise you to take Xiaowei to the temple.
我答應你，帶小唯去逍遙觀
Okay?
好啦嗎？
Sister Peirong.
佩蓉姐
I've got you a spell.
我給你求了一個驅鬼符
It expels demons and gives you peace.
可以保平安的
She gives it to you. Just put it on.
小唯送給你，你帶上吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Let's go.
走吧
Xiaorou, hand me the medical kit!
小柔，把藥箱拿過來
Xiaowei is hurt!
小唯弄傷了
Sister.
姐姐
You didn't hurt me. See, I'm fine!
你沒有剪到我，你看沒事
Lmpossible! I clearly saw her wound!
怎麼可能，我明明看到她的傷口
What're you talking about?
你又在說什麼呀？
She's not an evil demon, is she?
她不會是妖吧
She's surely fun, and charming.
她確是古靈精怪的，迷倒不少人
But how could she possibly be?
但怎麼可能是妖精啦？
Only you can tempt me.
只有你能迷倒我
I've sent you so many letters.
我寄了好多好多封信
Don't know if you got them.
也不知道你能不能收到
What's up now?
現在怎樣了？
Now, she's become...
如今
more friendly with everyone,
她和我身邊的人越來越好
and she's getting very close to Brother Sheng.
和生哥越來越親密
Anyone knows you suspect she's a demon?
那別人知不知道她是個妖？
How dare I tell anyone else?
我怎麼敢跟別人隨便亂說？
No one would believe me.
沒有人相信我
Demon?
妖？
You don't believe me, either?
你也不相信我？
I do, of course!
我怎會不相信你？
When did I ever disbelieve you?
我什麼時候沒相信過你？
What do you want me to do?
你想要我做什麼？
Find out the truth!
查出真相
What if she's really not a demon?
如果萬一知道她不是妖怎麼辦？
Then I'll admit I'm wrong.
那我就認
Please, Brother Yong!
拜託你啦，勇哥
Any money?
有沒有銀子呀？
Find me if you don't have enough.
不夠的話，再來找我
Lend me some money.
借些銀兩給我
No money? But you invited me for a drink!
你沒錢嗎？沒錢你請我吃飯？
You enjoyed it too, didn't you?
你不是吃得也很好嗎？
Hurry up!
快點，快點！
Be careful.
別灑了
Didn't I say you should wait for me?
不是說好等我回來的嗎？
Miss Xiaowei said...
小唯姐說…
Master's irritated...
老爺已經生氣啦
so we hurried to give the dishes.
所以我們才急著上菜的
Let me do it.
我來倒
Sister-in-law.
嫂子
Mistress.
夫人
Start the meal.
開菜
Let me do it.
我來
Where have you just been?
剛才你去哪裡？
Everybody's waiting for you.
大家都在等你
I've just...
剛剛…
Brother Wang, don't be upset with her.
王大哥，你不要生氣
Sister Peirong went to the beauty shop
其實佩蓉姐剛才是回了一趟慧妍齋
for some lavender
拿了一些蕙草干
to put under your pillow in a bag,
想做一個香袋放在你枕頭下面
so you can sleep well.
好讓你睡得安穩
It's New Year now.
都過年啦
Don't worry too much.
很多事，就不用那麼操心
I know.
我知道
Sister.
姐姐
Are you looking for this?
是在找這個嗎？
I must thank you today.
今天真的謝謝你
I'll give it to Brother Sheng.
我去交給生哥
I know who you've been to see.
我知道你去見誰
I won't tell Brother Wang.
我不會告訴王大哥的
Something is actually not what you think.
其實有些事情，也不是你想的那樣
Anyway,
總之
I'll tell you more about us later.
以後有機會，我再告訴你我們的事情
It's good as long as you're happy.
只要你開心就好了
Have a rest.
早點休息吧
I've made a box for you.
我替你做了一個盒子
Put the hearts inside and they'll be kept fresh.
以後心放在裡面，可以保持新鮮
Just put it there.
先放著吧
Brother Sheng asked me to draw the "heart-digger".
生哥讓我畫挖心人的圖
I must do it well.
所以我要好好畫才行
Remember that old fella surnamed Xia who chopped you?
你還記得砍你一刀的那個夏老頭嗎？
Isn't he dead?
他不是死了嗎？
His granddaughter is here in town.
他的孫女來了江都
Damn it! Their family never let me go.
討厭，他們這家人就永遠不肯放過我
Shall I kill her for you?
我替你殺了她？
Yes.
好呀
Don't smile.
不要笑
No murderer smiles.
殺人犯那有笑的
Don't move!
不要動嘛
You keep moving. How do I draw?
你動來動去，我怎麼畫？
Brother Yong, you should know something
勇哥，有些事情你應該知道
The dead bodies whose hearts...
所有遭開膛挖心的死者
are removed are all here.
屍體都在這裡
Brother Sheng has run out of ideas, so our Wang's Squadron...
生哥他也沒辦法，所以我們王家軍…
can only patrol every night.
也只能每夜宵禁巡邏
Wang's Squadron?
王家軍？
You've left for so long.
你都走了那麼久
Should we still call it "Pang's Squadron"?
難道還叫「龐家軍」嗎？
Wow!
嘩！
This man is a real pro!
這個高手很利害！
So accurate that he dug out the heart...
出手位置這麼準確
in a single cut!
一劍就把心挖出來
So I told Brother Sheng this couldn't be done by a human.
所以我告訴生哥，我懷疑不是人做的
You really believe in demons?
你真的信有妖？
If I were a yin yang master, I surely did...
我是兵陰陽家，當然信…
A demon! A demon here!
嘩！有妖，有妖呀！
Look at yourself. You believe in any crap!
你像什麼樣，你什麼都信
What do you not believe? Yin yang master!
你有什麼不信呀，陰陽家
Also, I suspect one person.
還有，我懷疑一個人
The woman Brother Sheng brought here - Xiaowei.
就是生哥帶回來那個女的-小唯
Don't you love her?
你不是很喜歡她嗎？
Not for sure!
哪有呀
You suspect her?
你懷疑她？
The killing spree began once she arrived.
她一來這裡，兇案就發生了
I really feel the evil "qi" from her!
我總覺得她有一股陰氣
- With suspicious background... - Alright...
來歷不明…      好啦…
Enough! You can set up a booth out there and fool the guys!
夠啦夠啦！你可以到街上擺攤了
Get off! You feel good staying in a coffin?
你下來吧，棺材裡很舒服嗎？
Get off!
下來吧
What he say is correct!
他說的都對
All done by evil demons!
這擺明都是妖幹的好事嘛
I too think evil demons did these.
我也說是妖做的
Don't listen to her foolish talk! It's all nonsense!
你別聽她胡言亂語，哪有這麼多妖
What foolish talk? I've seen before!
什麼胡言？這些我都見過的！
There're many demons in this world.
世間上有很多妖
Some're transformed from flowers, grasses and trees...
有的妖從花、草、樹木變的…
some from tigers, wolves, snakes, foxes...
有的妖是從虎、狼、蛇、狐變的…
and some from love and hatred...
有的妖因癡而生，有的妖因恨而生…
- Some are good, some are bad... - Don't kid me!
有好的，也有壞的…      小姐呀！
Demons kill with a sword?
妖會不會用劍殺人呀？
Why do humans kill humans for their hearts?
人為什麼會殺人取心呢？
What's your name? You seem very sure.
你哪位啊，口氣倒不小？
My name is Xia Bing.
我姓夏，叫夏冰
I'm a "Demon Buster".
我是「降魔者」…
My name is Pang Yong.
我叫龐勇
I don't believe in demons.
我不信妖這一套！
This sealed part of fox tail...
這段被封印的狐尾
will direct us to the "Beautiful Fox from the Sky".
是尋找「九霄美狐」的指南針
Once it senses a fox spirit in the vicinity,
因為當狐妖在狐尾的附近出現
it glares.
它就一定會發光的
This is what brought me here.
就是它帶我來到江都的
I'm sure the demon is still in this city.
我肯定這只妖一定還在城裡
Can you sense where the demon is?
那你感應到妖在哪裡？
Within a ten-mile radius of here.
在十里範圍之內
The entire city is only some ten miles long.
江都也不過才十幾里
Such a big range!
還有多少地方？
This is the last place!
這是最後一個地方
I've spent all my money on the case.
為了查案，我的錢都花光了
The Taoist priest died right here!
賽神仙，就是死在這
Also,
還有
all the murders occurred on the east side of the city.
兇案發生的地點全都在城東附近
Look.
你看
Not only that. They all surrounded commander's house!
不但是城東，還是包圍著都尉府？
Exactly!
對！
So what do we do next?
那我們下一步該怎麼辦？
Nothing to do with you.
這個與你無關
Miss, this is the official matter.
姑娘，這是官府的事
I think you needn't ask.
我想你不用過問了
He doesn't work for the government, either!
他也不是官府的人呀
Nothing to do with you as well.
這個也與你無關
Hey, where're you going?
喂，你去哪裡？
Nothing to do with you!
跟你無關！
Hey...
喂…喂…
I've used up my money!
我沒錢啦！
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
You're that demon?
你就是那個怪物？
Don't fool around!
你不要裝神弄鬼！
You wanna run?
你想走？
You so over there.
你們去那邊
Leave me alone! Get him!
不用管我，快去追…
Waiter! Waiter!
小二！小二！
Stop shouting. It's new year's day. Everybody's gone.
別叫了，大年初一，哪裡還有人啊
Do you come to drink or heal me?
喂！你是來喝酒，還是替我療傷的？
Don't panic. Just a small wound.
你別大驚小怪，只是皮外傷
What're you doing?
你幹嘛？
Why didn't you tell me you'd blow?
要噴你不告訴我？
I had wine in my mouth. I couldn't tell you.
我口裡有酒，怎麼說？
Have you seen enough?
你看夠了沒有？
Don't move.
不要動！
What?
幹嘛？
What... you...
幹嘛你？
Softly... softly...
輕輕輕…輕點…
Be quiet.
安靜點
It's done by a sword!
只是劍傷
Can a demon use a sword?
妖會用劍嗎？
Who say they can't?
誰說妖不用劍？
Softly, softy...
輕點，輕點，輕點…
How do you deal with them?
那你如何對付他們？
Ordinary demons can be finished by a single slash.
一般的妖，用喀，，就可以啦
What if they're not ordinary?
那不一般的呢？
This is this "Demon Rod".
這根「降魔棒」
My grandpa told me that...
我爺爺告訴我
its power is beyond limit...
只要遇到一個有能力的人
when it meets a capable person.
它便會威力無窮
That person is surely not you!
這個人肯定不是你
I can't take it out.
我拔不開它
Not me, either.
也不是我
I think your grandpa also couldn't.
我猜你爺爺，也沒有能力把它拔出來
Sure! How do you know?
是呀！你怎麼知道？
You don't believe my words?
你不相信我說的話？
Yes, yes. I dare not disbelieve!
信，信，怎麼敢不信
Don't get caught.
不要被人發現呀
I must've killed the gal...
要不是那醉鬼
if it weren't for that drunk.
我早就把那丫頭給宰了
So she was really helped from her old lover.
果然是舊情人來幫她的忙
Put Master's clothes in!
把老爺的衣服拿進去
No wonder she's getting bold!
怪不得她膽子越來越大
The sun is great. Dry it in the sun!
太陽真好，拿去曬一曬吧
Miss Xiaowei, who's getting bold?
小唯姐，誰膽子變大了？
I didn't say anything.
我沒說話
I'm sorry.
對不起
I can't go to the beauty store with you...
夫人要我留下來幫忙
coz mistress needs my help.
就不能陪你去慧妍齋了
Doesn't matter. You do your things.
沒關係，你去忙你的
I can go myself.
我可以自己去
Where did you go?
去哪了？
I... I just helped in the study...
我剛剛在書房幫忙…
You go to the kitchen, then.
那你去廚房吧
Yes!
是
Brother Yong, I've checked it.
勇哥，我查過了
There's a rich man called Gao Kun in another city.
蘇州城裡是有一個大戶叫高昆的
The whole family died of a plague three years ago.
三年前全家都因為瘟疫死了
He doesn't have a daughter. This woman's lying.
他根本沒有女兒，這個女人在說謊
Peirong, where's Xiaowei?
佩蓉，小唯呢？
In the beauty shop.
她在慧妍齋
Brother Yong, what do you find her for?
勇哥，你找小唯什麼事？
She's not what she claims to be!
她的身份是假的
You've brought a demon home!
你們把妖怪惹回家了
Demon?
妖
Brother Yong, you do believe a rumor like this?
勇哥，這樣的話你也信？
I just want to find out the truth.
我只想知道真相
Truth. Fine.
真相，好呀
I'll get you there and see the truth.
我帶你們去看，你們要的真相
The Gao family has no daughter! Who are you?
高家根本就沒有女兒，你到底是誰？
Xiahou Xiang is known to be wrong all the time!
夏侯向說話根本就沒有幾句是對的
Has he misunderstood you?
他是不是誤會你了？
That's right! Miss Xiaowei, just go ahead
對啊，小唯姑娘，你有什麼委屈
tell us your difficulties!
你就說出來吧
Xiaowei, don't be scared.
小唯，別怕
Tell us everything!
有什麼就說出來
I'm actually not the Gao family's daughter.
我確實不是什麼高家的女兒
I'm only...
我只不過是…
their maid.
他們的丫環
But I love being with you...
可是我又太喜歡跟你們在一起
and don't want you to look down upon me.
怕你們看不起我
That's why I made up such that stupid story.
所以一時糊塗就編了這個故事
Who else can verify what you said?
還有誰能證明你說的這一切？
No.
沒有
We can!
我們能證明！
We rescued her...
是我們從沙匪窩裡
from the lair of the desert's bandits.
把小唯姑娘救回來的
She'd have died if we it weren't for us!
要不是出手及時，她早就沒命了
- Yes! Yes... - Sure! We rescued her...
對！對…    就是呀，是我們救的…
Brother Wang,
王大哥
I did tell lies.
我是騙了你
But please don't banish me! Will you?
但請你不要趕我走，好不好？
I don't want to be alone.
我不想一個人
Get up.
起來
With me here, nobody dare bully you.
有我在這裡，沒有人敢欺負你
I'll chop your hands off and see if you're a demon!
我把你手砍下來，看你是不是妖
Brother Yong!
勇哥！
What're you doing? Are you crazy?
你想幹嘛？你是不是瘋了？
I just tested her. It's the back of the blade!
我是試她，這是刀背
I don't care what tricks you played. Xiaowei is my family!
我不管是不是刀背，小唯是我家人
Your family... so what about Peirong?
小唯是你家人，那佩蓉呢？
Peirong is your wife! She's been worried about you every day!
佩蓉是你夫人，她每天為你擔心受怕
Brother Yong.
勇哥
You still care that Peirong had chosen me!
你還那麼在意，佩蓉選擇了我
Bastard!
混蛋！
I'm not happy!
我就是不開心！
Coz Peirong has chosen the wrong one!
我不開心佩蓉選錯了人
You cold-hearted thing!
你這沒良心的東西！
They're already married.
他們都已經是夫妻了
I think you'd better give up.
我看你還是死了這條心吧
Shut up!
你閉嘴！
Obsessed by that woman!
色迷心竅的傢伙！
You've never seen a woman?
難道沒有見過女人？
Pang Yong!
龐勇！
It's my private matter. It's none of yours!
我王生的家事，不用你來管
I must care about the demon's case!
妖的事情，我就要管
This is a section of tail from a fox spirit.
這是一段，從狐妖身上斬下來的尾巴
Whenever a demon shows up, it glares.
只要有妖出現的地方，它就會發亮
It's always glaring. So we're all demons?
它還在亮，原來我們都是妖精？
I'm a "Demon Buster". Everything I said is real!
我是「降魔者」  ，我說的都是真的！
I don't believe it. Who does?
我不信，誰信？
The ghosts do!
鬼信！
I do!
我信！
I saw it with my own eyes!
是我親眼看到的
She knows black magic.
她會妖術
I hurt her hand by accident
我弄傷了她的手
and it healed up at once.
她的手可以無藥而愈
Later I told this to the Taoist priest.
之後我便把這個事情，告訴了賽神仙
He said you're a demon with high power.
他說你是妖，法術高強
On the very next day, he died...
之後第二天，他便死了…
I've been staying with you. I know more than anyone else.
我跟你朝夕相處，沒有人比我更清楚
I have an idea!
我有辦法
There's a "mark" on each demon,
妖的身上，都有「妖印」
Like human's birthmark.
像活的痣一樣
Dare you let us examine you?
你敢不敢讓我們驗明正身？
Miss Demon, are you scared?
妖精，怕了吧你？
Dare you?
你敢嗎？
I dare!
我敢！
I do as long as you won't suspect me.
只要你不誤會我，我就敢
Satisfied?
安心了吧？
Nothing to do with her. They're all my ideas.
這不關她的事，全是我的主意
I still have one more idea.
我還有一個辦法
Are you finished?
你還有完沒完？
For a fox spirit to sustain their human form,
狐妖要保持人形
they must swallow human hearts,
必須要吞食人心
which is why there're so many deaths with their hearts removed.
所以鎮上才會死了這麼多被挖心的人
Are you finished?
看你沒完沒了啦？
- Sure... - Are you wasting our time?
真是的…    你是不是在浪費時間？
What you mean is...
你的意思是…
If she has no heart to eat,
如果那個女的沒有人心吃
she'll reveal her true form?
就會露出原形？
Let's watch Miss Xiaowei for a while!
那我們就陪著小唯姑娘
See if she'll become a demon with no hearts to eat.
看她不吃人心，會不會原形畢露
I must let you know that you're wrong!
我要你們知道，你們是錯的
I'm not so stupid to keep a demon in my house!
我還沒有笨到，把妖精放到我的府裡
Don't make any mistakes.
你不要出錯
Even you don't believe me?
連你都不相信我？
I do.
信
Get in.
進去呀
I understand that
我明白
you're just concerned about me.
你是為了關心我
I'm sorry.
對不起
You should apologize so Xiaowei.
你應該說對不起的，是小唯
I'm so sorry...
對不起…
I'm sorry for you, sister.
是我對不起你，姐姐
I know why you suspect that I'm a demon.
我知道你為什麼會懷疑我是妖
You worry if I'll steal Brother Wang.
因為你怕我搶走王大哥
Yes, I really love him.
可是，我真的是很愛他
But don't get me wrong. I'll never oppose you.
但是你不要誤會，我不會跟你搶的
Please accept me as his concubine...
你們就收我為妾吧
Please...
求求你…
Xiaowei, just get up.
小唯，起來說話
Sister Peirong, I beg you...
佩蓉姐，我求求你…
Xiaowei.
小唯
There is only one Mrs. Wang.
王夫人只有一個
You should be so tired today.
你今天應該很累
Xiaorou.
小柔
Yes!
在！
Take Xiaowei back to her room.
送小唯姑娘回房間
Miss Xiaowei...
小唯姐
Stick with her! Even when she's in the toilet!
還不跟她進去，去茅房都要跟
Mrs. Wang.
王夫人
There is only one Mrs. Wang.
王夫人只有一個
Please get some rest, Miss Xiaowei.
小唯姐，早點休息吧
Okay.
好的
I have some good dim sum. You like it?
我這有一些好吃的點心，你吃嗎？
No, thanks!
謝了
You might try to poison me!
我怕你會毒死我
Do you still suspect me?
你是不是還是懷疑我是妖啊？
I never suspected you.
我從沒懷疑你是妖
I am sure you are!
我肯定你就是妖！
General! General!
將軍！將軍！
The heart digger has done it again!
挖心的又出現啦！
Xiaorou, you help me with it.
小柔，還是你來
Let Miss Xiaowei have some rest.
讓小唯姑娘休息一下
Come on.
來
Brother Yong.
勇哥
The guy killed some more people in a couple of days.
那個挖心的，這兩天又殺了幾個人
Our soldiers're placed everywhere, but...
雖然滿城都佈滿我們的兵，但是…
we still can't catch him.
還是沒有把他抓到
You can't catch him. He's a demon!
他是只妖，你當然抓不到
Demon?
妖？
Don't you mean Xiaowei's a demon?
你不是說小唯是妖精嗎？
You've been watching her all day.
你天天在府裡看著她
Why still deaths outside?
為什麼外面還有人死呢？
Who says there's only one demon?
誰說妖怪只有一個？
Another one?
又來一個啦？
Wang Sheng, what do you think?
王生，你有什麼想法？
I think he should be a kung fu expert.
我認為，他應該是個一等一的高手
Only you can seize him.
也只有你才能把他抓住
I sincerely hope you to stay.
我懇請你留下來
I, Peirong,
我和佩蓉
and all the citizens here will thank you.
還有全城的百姓，都會感激你
Please.
拜託啦
Peirong.
佩蓉
You persuade Brother Yong.
你就替我好好勸勸勇哥
I'm sorry.
對不起
Don't say sorry. I don't want you to say sorry.
不要說對不起，我不想聽你說對不起
You've done nothing wrong.
你沒有對不起任何人
I'm back...
其實我這次回來
only to see that you're happy.
最重要是見到你開心
You look good, aren't you?
你現在不是很好嗎？
Brother Yong.
勇哥
You're the best man ever.
你是一個最好的男人
Hope you'll find a woman better than me.
我希望你能找到一個比我更好的女人
Don't worry.
你不用替我擔心
I've been traveling around alone very well.
這幾年，我一個人生活不知道有多好
So free. And nothing to be anxious.
自由自在，無憂無慮
Let's talk later. I'll go help Wang Sheng now.
不說了，我去幫王生
Stupid man!
笨男人！
Miss Xia Bing, he's a good man.
夏冰姑娘，他是個好男人
Do treat him better.
你要對他好一點
Don't lump me with him! It's not what you think.
我和他的關係，不是你想那樣
I'm not interested in such a stupid shit.
我對這種笨男人，沒興趣
Put on our golden armors and we're forever the strongest.
穿金甲兮，遇強愈強
Sacrifice our lives for the sake of our parents.
拋頭顱兮，為爹為娘
Spill our blood...
灑熱血兮…
Xiahou Xiang!
夏侯向！
This time, I get plotted...
這一次，沒想到自己…
Mistress! Mistress!
夫人！夫人！
Mistress...
夫人…
My God! It's heard that Pang Yong killed Xiahou Xiang!
不好啦！聽說龐勇把夏侯向給殺了
Lmpossible!
怎麼可能？
The Mo Zhui guys personally saw it.
是莫追他們親眼看見的
Xiaohou Xiang is dead.
夏侯向死了
I know.
我知道
They suspect that I killed him.
他們懷疑我殺的
I know it as well.
我也知道
I don't believe, though.
可我不信
Under such circumstances,
到了這個地步
you'll suffer if you follow me.
你跟著我沒什麼好處的
Who follows you?
誰跟你在一起啦？
Now you're following me to catch the demon!
是你在跟著我去捉妖
Catch it? Are you confident?
捉妖？你有把握嗎？
No, for sure!
當然沒有呀
When had I ever been confident?
我什麼時候有過把握
But why're you still after him?
沒把握你還追著他不放？
You're not scared of death?
你不怕死啊？
I'm a Demon Buster.
我是降魔者
It's my duty.
我不可以不追的
Life gets better if you have a purpose.
心裡有個目標，做人也會開心點
You're right!
是呀
And you?
你呢？
What's your purpose?
你心裡的目標是什麼？
Seems that it's the same as yours now.
看來我現在的目標跟你一樣
His horse is still here. He must still be in the city.
馬還在，人一定還在城裡
You bring a team there.
你帶一隊人去那邊
- Yes! - Let's go!
好！      咱們走
- Go! - Take care, general!
走！      慢走，軍爺
Get some sleep.
睡吧
I'll go nowhere tonight. I'll stay with you.
今天晚上我哪裡都不去，在家裡陪你
Don't worry.
別擔心
I don't believe Brother Yong'd kill Xiahou Xiang, either.
我也不相信勇哥殺了夏侯向
I'll find him and ask him thoroughly.
只要把他找出來，問個清楚
I want to ask you,
我想問你
will you love her...
如果小唯不是妖的話
if Xiaowei is not a demon?
你會不會喜歡她？
How can Xiaowei be a demon?
小唯怎麼可能是妖精呢？
Okay... I promise.
好了好了，我答應你
I'll get more Taoist priests to check her out,
再去找幾個能降妖除魔的人來
okay?
好嗎？
You haven't answered me yet.
你還沒回答我呢
Will you love her?
你會愛上她嗎？
Whether she's a demon or woman,
不管她是人是妖
I won't.
都迷不到我
Rest assured.
放心吧
What's up?
怎麼啦？
Brother Wang.
王大哥
I think I need to go.
我想我是要離開
I've said too many that I shouldn't have.
我說了太多不該說的話
You forgot it?
你忘了嗎？
I said I'll look after you,
我說過我會一直照顧你
like my sister.
像妹妹一樣照顧你
Peirong will understand!
佩蓉也都知道的
Am I really that... useless?
我難道就這麼…一無是處？
How could you be?
怎麼會？
Everyone can see that Gao Xiang,
像高翔、荊平、荊安兄弟
Jing Ping and Jing An are attracted to you.
誰都看得出，他們喜歡你
I think that nobody'll ever dislike you
我想這天下間，不會…
in this whole world.
不會有人不喜歡你吧
But I only want you to love me.
可我想要你喜歡我
Can I not even become your concubine?
我難道連做你的妾都不配嗎？
It's me who's not qualified.
是我不配呀
Don't sell yourself short. You shouldn't be my concubine.
我怎麼能委屈你，要你做我的妾呢？
You should find a good man...
你應該好好找個人
who takes care of you and loves you.
好好照顧你，好好的愛你才是
Right?
對吧？
Have you ever loved me?
你喜歡過我嗎？
I don't need anyone else.
我不需要任何人
I don't need any status.
我也不要任何名分
I just want to be your woman,
我只想做你的女人
even ifjust once...
那怕只有一次…
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Alright.
好啦
You needn't worry if Xiaowei's a demon. Okay?
你也不用擔心小唯是妖精，好嗎？
What's wrong?
怎麼啦？
Why were you staying in her room?
你怎麼會在她房間？
I...
我…
- I just... - Don't need to say it.
我只是…      不用說啦！
I know she really loves you.
我知道她是真心的喜歡你
And I understand...
我都明白
It's not what you think...
其實不是這樣的…
It's all my fault.
是我不好
As a wife, I was jealous, maybe.
是我這個做妻子的不夠大方
If you love her too,
既然你們兩情相悅
then make her your concubine.
不如納她為妾吧
I don't!
我沒有！
Let me finish my words.
你就讓我把話說完吧
As her elder sister, I'll decide it for her.
讓我這個做姐姐的替她作主吧
It's you...
其實是你心裡…
who still don't believe I can do it.
不相信我做得到
General!
將軍…
Who let you come out?
誰讓你出來的？
Don't forget you're a demon.
你別忘了你是妖
Don't shed a tear for a man.
用不著為人動真感情
Now you're more stupid than that stupid woman!
你現在比那個蠢女人還要蠢
You know I love him?
我愛他，你知道嗎？
Do you know what's love,
你這個整天吃蒼蠅的傢伙
you fly eater?
知道什麼是愛嗎？
I know!
我知道
And I've told you, I love you.
我告訴過你，我愛你
But I don't love you!
可我不愛你
I told you long ago. You've been shameless enough to stay!
我早就告訴過你，是你自己賴著不走
Who gets you all those hearts without me?
沒有我，誰找心給你吃？
I'll live well without you!
沒有你，我一樣過得好好的
Now act like a man and leave.
如果你有骨氣的話，現在就走
Get away!
走呀！
Okay.
好
I'm sorry for what I've done.
我對不起你
I'll never disturb you!
以後我不會再纏著你
Go!
走！
- Mistress... - Mistress...
夫人…      夫人…
Sister Peirong, still staying up?
佩蓉姐，你還沒睡啊？
Sister Xiaowei.
小唯妹妹
I think there's one thing...
有一件事情
I must talk with you.
我想我還是應該跟你商量一下
You find me... for something?
你找我…有事嗎？
Now you know it all.
被你發現啦
Didn't you say I'm a demon? What do you fear?
你不是說我是妖嗎？你怕什麼？
Go tell everyone. Those who know must die, after all.
去告訴其他人吧，反正知道的都要死
Brother Gao, let's take a look outside.
高大哥，我們去外面看看
Be careful.
小心點
- Okay. - Go!
好      去吧
Mistress! Are you all right?
夫人，你沒事吧？
I'm fine.
沒事
What do you want?
你想怎麼樣？
Not made up my mind yet.
我還沒想好
Brother Gao.
高大哥
Miss Xiaowei...
小唯姑娘
Don't come in!
別進來！
Brother Gao, Sister Peirong said she saw a demon.
高大哥，佩蓉姐說她看到妖了
Demon? Where is it?
看到妖？在哪？
Right here!
在這
No!
不要！
Didn't you say you like me?
你不是說你喜歡我？
Can you give me your heart?
可以把心給我嗎？
Seen any demons eating a human heart?
看見過妖吃人心嗎？
Brother Sheng loves you. Don't hurt him!
生哥是愛你的，不要傷害他
It's useless as long as you, Mrs. Wang, is here.
沒有用的，有你這個王夫人在
That's nothing!
我不重要
I can let you be Mrs. Wang.
我的王夫人可以讓給你
Me?
讓給我？
Can you guarantee that you'll never come back?
你能保證你走了，就不再回來嗎？
I've seen you eat a human heart.
我已經看你吃了一顆人心
Can I still stay alive?
我還可以不死嗎？
Go ahead kill me!
殺了我吧！
You think I'm that stupid?
你以為我是笨蛋呀
If I kill you,
我要是殺了你
Brother Wang'd miss you forever.
王大哥就會掛念你一輩子
Drink this up.
喝了它
Go admit to be a demon killing all those guys.
告訴所有的人，他們都是你殺的
I'll be Mrs. Wang and you the demon.
你做妖，我來做王夫人
I can.
可以呀
But will you promise not to kill again?
那你以後可以不再殺人嗎？
I'm a demon. I'll grow old if I don't.
我是妖，不吃人心我會老的
Okay, I promise you.
好吧，我答應你
When I become Mrs. Wang,
只要我做了王夫人
I'll stay with him, grow old and die with him.
我會陪著王大哥，一起老死
You really love him?
你真的喜歡他？
Yes, I do.
我真愛他
Do keep your words.
你說話算話
If you regret, I'll kill everyone.
你要是後悔了，我會殺了所有的人
You don't even know what is love.
你根本就不懂，什麼叫做愛
A demon...
有妖怪…
Xiaorou! Xiaorou...
小柔！小柔…
Help! Help...
救命呀！救命呀…
Mistress...
夫人…
What's happening?
是怎麼一回事啊？
Hey! Stop!
別跑！站住！
Mistress, why is it you?
怎麼會是夫人？
I'm the demon. Go ahead kill me.
我是妖，你們殺了我吧
You all stop moving!
你們不要亂動！
Back off!
走開！
Or I'll kill you!
誰敢亂動，我就殺了誰！
Peirong, stand it! You'll be fine!
佩蓉！你要堅持住，你不會有事的
Master! Mistress is really the demon!
老爺，夫人她真的是妖呀
Xiaorou, don't talk anything nonsense.
小柔，你不要胡說
Has Sister Peirong... suffered from any strange disease?
佩蓉姐…是得了什麼病吧
Not her? So who killed Brother Gao?
不是妖？那是誰殺了高大哥？
Sure!
對！
We must revenge Brother Gao!
一定要為高大哥報仇！
She seems to have suffered from evil poison.
看來她是中了妖毒
It's graded by color.
妖毒是以顏色來辨別毒性的
The lighter the color, the more deadly it is.
顏色愈淡，毒性愈大
White is therefore the most poisonous of all.
所以白色，是妖毒中最厲害的
When the whole body turns white, one must die.
當白色漫延全身，便會斃命
Do you have so many ways? How to save her?
你不是有很多辦法嗎？怎麼救她？
You've woken up, Peirong. Feeling better?
你醒了，佩蓉？感覺好點嗎？
You all leave me.
你們走吧
Did Xiaowei do this?
是小唯干的嗎？
I myself...
是我自己
is the demon.
我才是妖
Don't speak nonsense!
你別亂說！
Don't worry. You'll be fine.
你放心，你不會有事的
She's a Demon Buster. She must be able to help.
她是降魔者，她一定有辦法的
Don't you have your family's treasure?
你不是有你的傳家之寶嗎？
Sure. My grandpa left me a lot.
對！我爺爺給了我很多傳家之寶
I...
我…
Not these.
不是這些
Your grandpa...
你爺爺…
he gave me that one treasure.
你爺爺留給你那一樣傳家之寶呢
Sure...
對…
Look! She really has the treasure!
看！她真的有傳家之寶
It can destroy the demons!
它能滅妖的
Come to think of it.
對了，我想起來了
My grandpa told me, once the demon is killed...
我爺爺告訴過我，只要把妖殺死…
the dark magic cast on human body should vanish...
妖施在人身上的妖術，就會消失的…
Can you hear it?
你聽到沒有？
Yes!
是的
You'd have used it if it was really useful.
有用的話，你們早就拿出來了
You cannot beat her.
你們是鬥不過她的
Don't worry.
別擔心
The killings should end with me.
我死了以後，就不會有人再死了
Stop speaking nonsense. I will have the way.
你不要亂說，我一定會有辦法的
Peirong!
佩蓉！
Peirong, I've taken back my sword!
佩蓉，我把刀拿回來了
You know how powerful it is?
你知道我的刀有多厲害
With it, I never lost!
刀在我手上從來沒輸過
You'll be saved once I kill the demon!
我殺了這個女妖，你就有救了
I'll chop her into pieces! Okay?
我把她砍死！好不好？
I'll ask you one more time.
我再問你一次
You're sure it's Xiaowei?
你是不是肯定是小唯？
I don't want any innocent deaths!
我不想錯殺無辜
You still don't believe me now?
你到現在還不相信我？
Okay, I'm going.
好，我現在就去
You take care of Peirong!
你照顧佩蓉
You're really going?
你真的要去？
I must go for sure.
我當然要去
You can't! You cannot kill her!
你不能去，你殺不了她的
Don't kid me!
你開什麼玩笑
Your grandpa cut off the fox spirit's tail.
你爺爺可以把狐狸尾巴砍下來
This sword's great.
我這把大刀這麼厲害
How could I not kill her?
憑什麼殺不了她？
My grandpa cut her using his own blood!
我爺爺是用身上的血，才能砍到她的
We, the "Demon Busters",
我們世世代代的「降魔者」
have bloods
身上流著的血
which can specially kill demons.
都是有斬妖能力的
If you do want to kill Xiaowei,
你要是真想殺小唯
bring me there.
帶我一起去
Wang Sheng,
王生
do you know what's happening?
你到底知不知道發生什麼事？
Miss, don't get there!
小姐，不要過去！
Are you really a demon?
你真的是妖？
Yes.
對
You killed Gao Xiang?
高翔是你殺的？
I killed everyone.
所有的人都是我殺的
We must revenge Brother Gao!
我們要為高大哥報仇！
You want to kill her, kill me first.
你們要殺她，先殺我
Revenge Brother Gao!
為高大哥報仇！
An eye for an eye!
殺人償命！
Shut up!
閉嘴！
She's a demon. I must kill her!
她是妖，我一定會殺了她！
But how can I give her up as a husband?
但作為丈夫，我怎能放棄她？
Put down the knife!
把刀放下！
Put it down!
放下！
Put down the knife first!
先把刀放下！
Peirong
佩蓉
I must take all the responsibility with you!
不管你做了什麼，我們都一起承擔
I'm a demon.
我是妖！
I killed so many and I deserve it.
我殺了那麼多人，死有餘辜！
You're my wife.
你是我夫人
Whether you're demon or woman, I love you.
不管你是人是妖，我都愛你
I love you forever!
我永遠愛你！
No.
不要
Promise me.
答應我
Live well.
一定要好好活著
Live on for me...
為我活著…
Evil woman!
妖女！
You all see it? She is the real demon!
你們看到了沒有？她才是妖呀！
What? Leave me!
你幹嘛？放手！
You can't kill her!
你殺不了她的！
What're you doing?
你幹嘛？
Go!
去呀！
Give her back to me.
還給我
If you love me,
如果你愛我
give Peirong back to me.
把佩蓉還給我
If you love her so much,
如果你那麼愛她
why don't you die with her?
為什麼不跟她一起死？
I'll die.
我死了
Get her here!
把她救回來
Will you believe her?
你不要再相信她？
If Peirong dies,
佩蓉死了
I'll die with her.
我跟她一起死
If she comes back to life,
要是她能活過來
Tell her that...
你告訴她
I haven't been a good husband.
我不是個好丈夫
I've failed to protect her.
我沒有好好保護她
I love you,
我愛你
but I'm married with Peirong.
可是我已經有佩蓉啦
No!
不要呀！
Brother Sheng!
生哥…
What's this?
這是什麼？
You saved them with the thousand-year spirit!
你竟然用修行上千年的靈來救他們
You're a demon.
你是妖
They won't let you go even...
就算你救了他們
if you saved them!
他們也不會放過你的
How can a demon gets ture love in the world?
妖怎麼可能在人間找到真愛呢？
I'll get you out of here...
等我殺了他們
once I kill them all!
我帶你回去
Look! He has a shadow!
看！他有影子！
Take it!
接著！
Hurry up! Kill him!
快點！殺了他！
Do it! Just do it...
出手！出手呀…
It doesn't matter if I die. You must kill him!
我死沒關係的，你一定要殺了他
Take Peirong's spirit back and save her.
拿回靈氣，救回佩容
Kill me. Do it quickly!
出手，出手殺我！
Do it...!
動手呀…
Xiaowei!
小唯…
Many hatreds in the world...
世間許多的恩恩怨怨
can be finished without killing.
不是靠殺光才能完結的
I now realize why...
我現在才明白
I couldn't exert all my energy...
我為什麼一直都發揮不了
of a Demon Buster.
降魔者的能力
It's because I've been bearing hatred.
因為我一直都帶著仇恨
Go ahead save them.
把他們救回來吧
General, general...
將軍，將軍…
Are you okay, general?
沒事嗎，將軍？
Master, are you okay?
老爺，怎麼樣啦？
- Brother Dabao, are you okay? - Mistress...
大保哥，你怎麼樣啦？      夫人…
- General, are you fine? - Brother Dabao...
將軍，怎麼樣？      大保哥…
Mistress, it's fine now.
夫人，沒事了
- Brother Yong! - Brother Yong!
勇哥！      勇哥…
Brother Yong!
勇哥！
What's wrong with you? Brother Yong!
你怎麼了？勇哥！
Wake up... Brother Yong!
你醒醒呀…勇哥！
- Brother Yong! - Wake up...
勇哥！      你醒醒呀…
Brother Yong! Wake up...
勇哥！你醒醒呀…
Brother Yong...
勇哥…
Don't shake me anymore or I'm surely dying!
不要再搖了，不死也快被你搖死啦
I'm so tired after the long fight.
打了這麼久，我都累了
You're sure you don't want to stay?
真的不留下來？
There're still many places I want to go.
我還有很多地方想去
Me too.
我也很想去
I'm leaving.
走啦
Take care!
保重
Where're you going?
準備去哪？
The world's so big. I can go wherever I want.
天大地大，想去哪都可以
You seem to have a gift for catching demons.
我看你挺有捉妖天分的
Hey
怎樣？
Wanna catch demons with me?
有沒有興趣跟我一起去捉妖呀？
Why don't you call me master?
還不快叫聲師父
You're not qualified...
你那些三腳貓功夫
with all those mediocre skills.
憑什麼當我師父？
I'm more experienced than you.
我捉妖的經驗比你豐富多了
What're you looking at?
看什麼？
Put off your cap and you look very much like a woman.
發現你不戴帽子，挺像個女人
Not bad, not bad!
不錯，不錯